<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
<channel>
  <title>LaTeXDraw news</title>
  <description>The last news about the LaTeXDraw Project</description>
  <link>http://latexdraw.sourceforge.net</link>
  <language>en</language>
  <image>
    <title>LaTeXDraw news</title>
    <url>http://latexdraw.sourceforge.net/images/banniere.png</url>
    <link>http://latexdraw.sourceforge.net</link>
    <width>136</width>
    <height>32</height>
    <description>A graphical PSTricks code generator/editor</description>
  </image>
  <atom:link href="http://latexdraw.sourceforge.net/LaTeXDraw-news.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

  <item>
    <title>Exporting as PS/PDF on Windows</title>
    <author>arno_b@users.sourceforge.net (arno_b)</author>
    <pubDate>Sun, 14 sep 2014 09:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <guid>http://latexdraw.sourceforge.net/index.html#NEWS47</guid>
	 <link>http://latexdraw.sourceforge.net/index.html#NEWS47</link>
    <description>Miktex is certainly the widely-used LaTeX distribution on Windows. Some LaTeX binaries (pdfcrop and ps2eps notably) have a dependency to an application not installed by default by Miktex: perl. So, Windows users that do not have perl installed cannot use pdfcrop and ps2eps. They, therefore, may not be able to export as PDF/PS using LaTeXDraw. It seems that the only solution is to install perl: http://strawberryperl.com/.
To known whether pdfcrop and ps2eps work, you can check them by looking at the text in the tab "System" (menu "Help" -> "About LaTeXDraw").
I will look at avoiding such a new installation for the next release.</description>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>LaTeXDraw 3.2.0 released</title>
    <author>arno_b@users.sourceforge.net (arno_b)</author>
    <pubDate>Sun, 14 sep 2014 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <guid>http://latexdraw.sourceforge.net/index.html#NEWS46</guid>
	 <link>http://latexdraw.sourceforge.net/index.html#NEWS46</link>
    <description>This new version fixes major bugs. I did not have the time to finish the support of PSPlot functions. It will be part of the next release for sure.
Amongst the fixed bugs, the biggest one is certainly a bug related to the PDF/PS export on Windows 8.1.
Give an eye to the release note for more details (https://launchpad.net/latexdraw/3.x/3.2).</description>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>LaTeXDraw 3.1.0 released</title>
    <author>arno_b@users.sourceforge.net (arno_b)</author>
    <pubDate>Mon, 27 jan 2014 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <guid>http://latexdraw.sourceforge.net/index.html#NEWS45</guid>
	 <link>http://latexdraw.sourceforge.net/index.html#NEWS45</link>
    <description>This new version brings important changes and fixes major bugs. The new features are: Opacity and strokeopacity attributes are now supported. That permits to set the opacity of colours for the line border and the filling; The size of drawing area is no more limited to the size of the drawing. Additional boundaries are now provided around the drawing area to ease the editing; In complement to the previous change, a page (US letter only for the moment) is painted; When zooming using the mouse, the zoom process follows the pointer. The zoom increment, min, and max values have been changed to fit this new feature; Like many drawing applications, the view point of the drawing area can be move using the middle button of the mouse (or both the right and left buttons in some cases). It is more convenient than using the scroll bars; Better rendering performance; Ukrainian translation added; A menu item has been added to go to the latexdraw manual; A text field that contains the LaTeX compilation error log has been added to the text toolbar.
Regarding the fixed bugs, the major one is the non-creation of LaTeX text on Windows 7 and 8.
Give an eye to the release note for more details(https://launchpad.net/latexdraw/3.x/3.1).</description>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>Problem with LaTeX text rendering on Windows</title>
    <author>arno_b@users.sourceforge.net (arno_b)</author>
    <pubDate>Sat, 18 jan 2014 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <guid>http://latexdraw.sourceforge.net/index.html#NEWS44</guid>
	 <link>http://latexdraw.sourceforge.net/index.html#NEWS44</link>
    <description>If the native LaTeX rendering works like a charm on Linux, it seems that it does not work correctly on Windows.
I just fixed an issue that blocked that feature on Windows Seven but I do not have a Windows 8 to test that.
So, do not hesitate to download the latest devolopment version (https://ci.inria.fr/malai/job/latexdraw/lastBuild/net.sf.latexdraw$latexdraw.core/) to test the LaTeX rendering on Windows (Seven, 8) and MacOSX, and send me an email or use the forum to give me feedback!</description>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>LaTeXDraw 3.0.0 released</title>
    <author>arno_b@users.sourceforge.net (arno_b)</author>
    <pubDate>Sun, 23 dec 2013 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <guid>http://latexdraw.sourceforge.net/index.html#NEWS43</guid>
	 <link>http://latexdraw.sourceforge.net/index.html#NEWS43</link>
    <description>It is about time. Latexdraw 3.0 has been released today. More than 3 years without any stable release. As I said previously Latexdraw has been totally rewritten to be more usable and easy to maintain in the future. See below for the new features and give an eye to the release note. So use it!</description>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>For testing purposes only: LaTeXDraw 3.0.0 beta 1 released</title>
    <author>arno_b@users.sourceforge.net (arno_b)</author>
    <pubDate>Sun, 1 apr 2013 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <guid>http://latexdraw.sourceforge.net/index.html#NEWS42</guid>
	 <link>http://latexdraw.sourceforge.net/index.html#NEWS42</link>
    <description>The first beta release is out. Many bugs have been fixed, many others remain. So, let's test it and hope it would be the last beta before the final release.</description>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>For testing purposes only: LaTeXDraw 3.0.0 alpha 5 released</title>
    <author>arno_b@users.sourceforge.net (arno_b)</author>
    <pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2013 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <guid>http://latexdraw.sourceforge.net/index.html#NEWS41</guid>
	 <link>http://latexdraw.sourceforge.net/index.html#NEWS41</link>
    <description>Ok ok folks. Almost one year without any release... If you want to blame someone, blame Blizzard to have released Diablo III in April 2012 and my job ^^. More seriously this release re-introduces the conversion of pstricks code into shapes, and fixed several and annoying bugs such as the pdf-blank-page bug. Just as a reminder, this branch 3.0 is almost a complete rewriting of the application to ease the future developments. Thats' why it takes so long. The version 3.0 is almost feature complete. So the next release will be a beta one and will bring bug fixes, performance and usability improvements.</description>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>For testing purposes only: LaTeXDraw 3.0.0 alpha 4 released</title>
    <author>arno_b@users.sourceforge.net (arno_b)</author>
    <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2012 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <guid>http://latexdraw.sourceforge.net/index.html#NEWS40</guid>
	 <link>http://latexdraw.sourceforge.net/index.html#NEWS40</link>
    <description>Fourth alpha just released. Still for testing purposes only. This version: several Windows Seven bugs fixed; can customise grids and free hand shapes using widgets; can change the angles of arcs using their handlers; can reuse and create templates; the PSTricks parameter 'showpoints' supported for Bézier curves. Test it! One more alpha version is expected to (re-)support PSTricks import. Then, beta versions will be prepared to fix issues.</description>
  </item>


  <item>
    <title>For testing purposes only: LaTeXDraw 3.0.0 alpha 3 released</title>
    <author>arno_b@users.sourceforge.net (arno_b)</author>
    <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2012 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <guid>http://latexdraw.sourceforge.net/index.html#NEWS39</guid>
	 <link>http://latexdraw.sourceforge.net/index.html#NEWS39</link>
    <description>Third alpha just released. Still for testing purposes only. I was pretty busy these last weeks so that this release does not contain a lot of improvements: can rotate shapes; can customise axes; can customise the drawings' properties. Another alpha is excepted in a couple of weeks.</description>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>For testing purposes only: LaTeXDraw 3.0.0 alpha 2 released</title>
    <author>arno_b@users.sourceforge.net (arno_b)</author>
    <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2012 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <guid>http://latexdraw.sourceforge.net/index.html#NEWS38</guid>
	 <link>http://latexdraw.sourceforge.net/index.html#NEWS38</link>
    <description>Second alpha just released. Still for testing purposes only (piece of advice ;)). A lot of bugs were fixed, can join/separate shapes, can customise arrows, better text thumbnail resolution, progress bars,... A third alpha is expected in 4 weeks.</description>
  </item>


  <item>
    <title>For testing purposes only: LaTeXDraw 3.0.0 alpha 1 released</title>
    <author>arno_b@users.sourceforge.net (arno_b)</author>
    <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2012 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <guid>http://latexdraw.sourceforge.net/index.html#NEWS37</guid>
	 <link>http://latexdraw.sourceforge.net/index.html#NEWS37</link>
    <description>Whooooooooooo! Finally a release. It's about time. Ok ok, this is not a stable release but a preview for testing purposes only. LaTeXDraw 3.0.0 alpha 1 has been released with a lot of improvements such a native support of LaTeX text, pdf export on Macos has been fixed, etc. You can get the files and the release note there: https://sourceforge.net/projects/latexdraw/files/beta%20testing/3.0.0%20alpha1/. There is still a lot of features not yet re-introduced in 3.0.0 (for your memory: LaTeXDraw has been completely rewritten for the 3.0.0 version), such as: it is not possible to rotate shapes yet; no PSTricks import; no recent files; some widgets are still missing for modifying some shapes' attributes; etc. You can report any problem there (https://launchpad.net/latexdraw) or there (http://sourceforge.net/tracker/?group_id=156523). I will release a new alpha version at the end of February.</description>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>Native support of LaTeX text</title>
    <author>arno_b@users.sourceforge.net (arno_b)</author>
    <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2011 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <guid>http://latexdraw.sourceforge.net/index.html#NEWS36</guid>
	 <link>http://latexdraw.sourceforge.net/index.html#NEWS36</link>
    <description>More than one year without any release and post... Shame on me. LaTeXDraw 3.0 in on the road and a first beta should be released before the end of this year. This release takes a lot of time because I am completely rewritting LaTeXDraw: the code of 2.0 is really awful and I wanted to integrate the results of my PhD into LaTeXDraw in order to improve this last. The most important feature of LaTeXDraw 3.0 will be the native support of LaTeX text. It means that you will be able to write LaTeX text as in your favourite LaTeX editor. The text will be rendered in LaTeXDraw as in your final pdf or ps document. For example, in the following screen-shot I added a text in the drawing and typed a formula. Once typed, the text is compiled in LaTeX to be rendered in LaTeXDraw. This idea is strongly inspired by Lyx ;). Of course, if you want to use LaTeX commands coming from various packages, you can add \usepackage{} commands as it is already possible in LaTeXDraw 2.0. You can also discover in the screen-shots others new features; but I will speak about them in next posts soon.</description>
  </item>


  <item>
    <title>latexdraw 2.0.8 available</title>
    <author>arno_b@users.sourceforge.net (arno_b)</author>
    <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2010 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <link>http://latexdraw.sourceforge.net/index.html#NEWS35</link>
	 <guid>http://latexdraw.sourceforge.net/index.html#NEWS35</guid>
    <description>This release fixes some issues, notably a problem occuring while exporting as pdf (again...) using pdfcrop. This release is close to the 2.0.7 release because of the Debian feature freeze that will occur soon.</description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>latexdraw 2.0.7 available</title>
    <author>arno_b@users.sourceforge.net (arno_b)</author>
    <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2010 19:47:00 GMT</pubDate>
	<link>http://latexdraw.sourceforge.net/index.html#NEWS34</link>
   <guid>http://latexdraw.sourceforge.net/index.html#NEWS34</guid>
	  <description>This release fixes the issue that did not allow the export as pdf documents on Windows. By the way on Windows, to export as pdf using pdfcrop you need a perl interpreter installed such as strawberryperl (http://strawberryperl.com/). About the problem concerning a text that contains special characters (for instance the ampersand character), latexdraw will not escape these characters for two simple reasons: 1) a text shape in latexdraw must be formatted in latex since latexdraw is not an interface to latex as lyx. 2) If we escape special characters, how will we be able to use these special characters, for instance to create a tabular?</description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>latexdraw 2.0.5 available</title>
    <author>arno_b@users.sourceforge.net (arno_b)</author>
    <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2009 18:21:00 GMT</pubDate>
	<link>http://latexdraw.sourceforge.net/index.html#NEWS32</link>
   <guid>http://latexdraw.sourceforge.net/index.html#NEWS32</guid>
	  <description>This release fixes some problems. It also allows to export a drawing using pdflatex and pdfcrop; this feature allows to crop the generated pdf document.</description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>latexdraw 2.0.4 available</title>
    <author>arno_b@users.sourceforge.net (arno_b)</author>
    <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2009 16:32:00 GMT</pubDate>
	<link>http://latexdraw.sourceforge.net/index.html#NEWS31</link>
   <guid>http://latexdraw.sourceforge.net/index.html#NEWS31</guid>
	  <description>This release fixes some problems related to the pdf export: freezes occured on XP/Vista while exporting, weird pdf/ps title, etc.). It also brings the Polish localisation; thanks Szemek for that!</description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>latexdraw 2.0.3 available</title>
    <author>arno_b@users.sourceforge.net (arno_b)</author>
    <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2009 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
	<link>http://latexdraw.sourceforge.net/index.html#NEWS30</link>
   <guid>http://latexdraw.sourceforge.net/index.html#NEWS30</guid>
	  <description>Finally! latexdraw 2.0.3 is just released and brings a great (in my opinion) feature: the ability to export a drawing as pdf and ps using your latex distribution. To sum up, a latex document, containing your drawing, is created and compiled into a pdf or a ps document. You can then insert it into your main latex document as a picture (pstricks packages are no more needed and the pdflatex command can be used).
This release also fixes some problems for more information) and the Italian localisation is now available!</description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Thank for donations</title>
    <author>arno_b@users.sourceforge.net (arno_b)</author>
    <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2008 15:58:00 GMT</pubDate>
	<link>http://latexdraw.sourceforge.net/index.html#NEWS29</link>
   <guid>http://latexdraw.sourceforge.net/index.html#NEWS29</guid>
	  <description>I would like to thank Frank Petitjean and Martin Schonger for their donations to the latexdraw project. It is always a motivation to receive messages like 'thank for your editor, it helps me' or donations (even very small donations). Everyone can make a donation using paypal or by sending a cheque (ask the address by mail) if you are french.</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>Need help to translate :p</title>
    <author>arno_b@users.sourceforge.net (arno_b)</author>
    <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2008 15:58:00 GMT</pubDate>
	<link>http://latexdraw.sourceforge.net/index.html#NEWS28</link>
   <guid>http://latexdraw.sourceforge.net/index.html#NEWS28</guid>
	  <description>If you speak Spanish, Italian, German, Japanese, and so on, you can help to translate latexdraw in your language. Such help can be a correction of a translated string or the translation of untranslated strings. The process is simple: to make translations you just need to create an account on launchpad and to set your language(s). Then you can translate latexdraw (and any program which is on lauchpad such as Ubuntu, Gnome,...). See https://translations.launchpad.net/latexdraw/. If you find that a translation is not correct, you can modify it too. </description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>And now what?</title>
    <author>arno_b@users.sourceforge.net (arno_b)</author>
    <pubDate>Fri, 1 Aug 2008 11:58:00 GMT</pubDate>
	<link>http://latexdraw.sourceforge.net/index.html#NEWS27</link>
   <guid>http://latexdraw.sourceforge.net/index.html#NEWS27</guid>
	  <description>2.0 is now released, but certainly the most important release (for me) will be the 2.1. This future version will complete the work began in 2.0, such as the rewrite of the graphical library and of the undo/redo manager. Almost all of the original code has been rewritten in order the have a stout framework to easily implement more PSTricks and graphical stuffs. Because of that, the final user will see only minor changes. But after 2.1, 2.2 will return to provide PSTricks, LaTeX and graphical features such as maybe the pgf export, and some requested features.</description>
  </item>
  
  <item>
    <title>LaTeXDraw 2.0.0</title>
    <author>arno_b@users.sourceforge.net (arno_b)</author>
    <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2008 14:46:00 GMT</pubDate>
	<link>http://latexdraw.sourceforge.net/index.html#NEWS26</link>
   <guid>http://latexdraw.sourceforge.net/index.html#NEWS26</guid>
	  <description>The stable release of the 2.0 series is now release. It fixes some problem from the last beta version. Feel free to report any problem you find.
Look at the release note for more details. The more important things are certainly the use of the SVG format as the default format, the alignement and distribution of figures.</description>
  </item>
</channel>
</rss>
